In the first lesson,
在第一节课
when ranges were introduced,
当我们介绍区域时
I mentioned that it's possible to name ranges instead
我提到可以对区域命名
of referencing them by column and row addresses.
不必使用列和行地址来引用它们
To demonstrate the usefulness of named ranges,
为了展示命名区域的作用
we'll go back to the fruit stand spreadsheet.
我们再回到水果摊电子表格
I've changed it a bit with formatting and I've given it dates instead of order numbers.
我对格式稍加修改 并将订单编号改成了日期
There are four different fruits for sale at the fruit stand,
水果摊上有四种不同的水果
and likewise for item prices.
价格也是四种
I've also chosen names I want to use for the prices in my formulas.
我还选择了要在公式中使用的价格名称
I've chosen Apple price, Orange price, etc.
我选择了 apple_price orange_price 等等
because that's more descriptive than
因为比我将创建的命名区域用到的
simply apple or orange for the name ranges I am going to create.
apple 或 orange 更具描述性
The basic method to name a cell or range is to select the cell or range.
对单元格或区域进行命名的基本方法是选中单元格或区域
I'm going to select the cell with apple price in it,
我将选中具有苹果价格的单元格
and then go to the formula menu and click define name.
然后转到“公式”菜单并点击“定义名称”
I have a place to type in the name I want to use,
我可以在这里输入想要的名称
but Excel has already assumed I will want to use
但是 Excel 已经推断出我想要使用
the text from the adjacent cell to be my label.
相邻单元格里的文本作为标签
Excel also shows the range address that will be named.
Excel 还显示出了将被命名的区域地址
It includes the sheet name followed by an exclamation point,
包含工作表名称 紧跟着感叹号
followed by the absolute address.
然后是绝对地址
That's what we want here,
我们要的就是这个地址
so I'll just accept it with an OK. Now I have
因此接受该地址并点击确定
a cell that I can reference not only by its column and row which still works,
现在该单元格不仅可以用行和列来引用
but by the name apple price.
而且可以用名称“apple_price”
If I select that cell it even shows up in the name box over here on
如果我选择该单元格 左侧名称框中甚至显示出该名称
the left to confirm that this cell is named, apple price.
确认该单元格名称为 apple_price
For the other prices,
对于其他价格
I can repeat the process.
可以重复相同的流程
But in Excel there's a better way which I'll use for the remaining prices.
但是在 Excel 中 还有更好的方式来设定剩余的价格
Select the name and price cells,
选择名称和价格单元格
go to the formula menu and click on Create from selection.
转到“公式”菜单并点击“根据所选内容创建”
A dialog pops up and excel once
系统弹出一个对话框
again has assumed I want to use the left column for the name,
excel 再次推断我想要使用最左列作为名称
so I'll say OK. Now,
我将点击确定
all the price cells have names and we can see them in the name box.
现在所有价格单元格都具有名称 我们可以在名称框中看到这些名称
When we created our income calculation for the fruit stand before,
之前 当我们为水果摊创建收入计算公式时
we went through the task of setting the prices as absolutes when creating the formula.
我们将价格设为了绝对地址
Here it is and it's long and it's pretty hard to tell exactly what's going on.
公式是这样的 很长并且很难看出其中的含义
I'm going to rewrite the formula using named ranges.
我将使用命名区域来重写该公式
Again, we have the number of apples times the price which is apple price.
我们将苹果数量乘以价格 也就是 apple_price
I just start typing and when it appears,
我开始输入内容
press tab to autocomplete.
按下 Tab 键自动填充
I'll continue with each until I have them all in the formula.
继续对每个水果进行修改 直到输入整个公式
There, that's much more readable.
现在更容易读懂了
I can see at a glance what this formula is doing and I'll just fill it down.
我可以快速明白该公式的作用 向下填充
That was one used for named ranges,
这就是命名区域的一个用途
identifying some single values by name that we went to use in formulas.
用名称来识别我们将在公式中用到的单个值
Named ranges are also useful for naming a larger range
命名区域还可以用来命名更大的区域
to use for lookups and we'll see how to do that next.
并用于查找 接下来我们将了解如何执行这一操作